https://www.bas.ac.uk/about-this-site/privacy-cookie-policy/

Skip to content
Toggle navigation
About About BASOur Vision and MissionOur organisationOur Corporate & Innovation teamsOur Science teamsOur cultural valuesEquality, Diversity and InclusionDiversity in UK Polar ScienceOur national capabilityOur historyOur eventsContact BASPublic information servicesEducationAntarcticaThe Antarctic TreatyBritain in AntarcticaEnvironmental protectionGeographyTourismWildlifeDiscovering AntarcticaPolar fieldwork opportunitiesThe ArcticBritain in the ArcticUK Arctic Research StationScience of the ArcticBusiness of the ArcticGeography, wildlife and tourismDiscovering the ArcticArctic fieldwork opportunities
Science Our researchOur science strategyResearch topicsResearch projectsResearch modelsResearch collaborationsFellowsOur research facilitiesFunding and awardsApplying BAS science to global challengesOpportunities for polar fieldworkHow to applyOpportunities for polar ship researchUK National Committee on Antarctic ResearchScience and innovationAurora Innovation CentreOur national capabilityTechnology, tools and methodsScience and societyOur research impactScience into policyPublic engagement in researchEducationScience briefingsOur eventsScience, students and postgradsNERC Doctoral Training OpportunitiesScience conferences and eventsOur science teamsAtmosphere, Ice and Climate teamBiodiversity, Evolution and Adaptation teamEcosystems teamGeology and Geophysics teamIce Dynamics and Palaeoclimate teamPalaeo Environments, Ice Sheets and Climate Change teamPolar Oceans teamSpace Weather and Atmosphere teamResearch Development and Support teamResearch outputsDatasetsResearch papers
Data Explore polar dataFind datasetsData systemsPolar collectionsMapsBAS publicationsBAS imagesData as artUK Polar Data CentreAbout the teamData collaborationsData depositMetadata guidanceData citation and publishingSupport for research grantsOperational data management  Data teams at BASArchives ServiceBAS LibraryMapping and GISUK Polar Data CentreWeb & ApplicationsData centre contacts
Polar operations Sites and facilitiesOfficesResearch stationsResearch shipsAircraft capabilityVehiclesAntarctic infrastructure modernisationInfrastructure Project Management TeamsPolar OperationsOur operational strategyOur operational teamsOperational collaborationsEngineering and technologyPolar fieldwork opportunitiesHow to applyPre-deployment trainingLife in the polar regionsCamping and deep-field workingFoodClothingHealthTelecommunicationsVirtual toursInformation for PilotsPeople
News & media News and mediaNews and Press ReleasesLatest blogsLatest eventsResources for journalistsScience briefingsPicture galleriesAntarctic video galleryMapsMedia visitsCommunications TeamPress Office contactsCreative Services Contacts
Jobs Latest vacanciesJobs in AntarcticaCareers at BASScienceEngineering and technology jobsOperational supportMarinersPilotsContact HRWork experience opportunitiesOpportunities for studentsOpportunities for collaborationWorking for BASOur cultural valuesEquality, Diversity and InclusionDiversity in UK Polar ScienceEmployee benefitsLife in CambridgeLife in the polar regionsFeatured VacanciesPolar Climate ScientistHealth and Safety ManagerPolar Operations Support Team AssistantStation Support AdministratorAssistant Management Accountant – Science & InnovationContact BAS
Toggle search form visibilitySearch the site
Submit search
Submit search
BAS > About this site > Privacy & Cookie Policy
Privacy & Cookie PolicyPrivacy PolicyBAS’s website logs the user’s IP address which is automatically recognised by the web server.In the interests of preventing abuse and the sending of SPAM, we monitor the use of the “Email to a Friend” facility and may record email addresses entered into the form. Under no circumstances will any email addresses be sold or transferred to a third party.We will not collect any information about you except that required for conducting business with you, or system administration of the Web server. The information collected will not be sold or rented; nor will it be shared with third parties except where we are required by the Government to audit website usage data using an independent auditor (ABCe), and the information will be held securely by them. More information about why we measure and audit website traffic and the auditing process is available on the Central Office for Information website.This privacy policy only covers the British Antarctic Survey’s public corporate website (pages at the web address www.bas.ac.uk and www.antarctica.ac.uk). Other links within this site to other websites are not covered by this policy.Cookie PolicyWe use cookies to collect information about your activity on the website. Cookies do not contain any personal information. If you choose not to accept the cookie, this will not affect your access to any of the facilities on this website.Our Use of CookiesThis site uses Google Analytics and Piwik, an open source web analytics software program, to gather statistical information. Opt-out of using Google Analytics.For more information about how Piwik process this information, visit www.piwik.org.We use CloudFlare to serve our DNS and cached page content. This improves the performance of the site. Read more information about CloudFlare’s use of cookies.You can find out more about how we use cookies on our site.How to control and delete cookiesWe will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.However, if you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our websites, or indeed any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how.Alternatively, you may wish to visit AboutCookies.org – external link – which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your machine as well as more general information about cookies.Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our website.If you wish to view your cookie code, just click on a cookie to open it. You’ll see a short string of text and numbers. The numbers are your identification card, which can only be seen by the server that gave you the cookie. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone, you will need to refer to your handset manual.To opt-out of third parties’ collection of data during your visit to our website, please refer to their websites for further information.Summary of termsBrowserUsed to locate and display Web pages via a software application. The most popular ones are Microsoft Internet Explorer and Mozilla Firefox.CookieMessage given to a web browser by a web server. The message is then stored by the browser at a location on the user’s hard disc. Each time the browser requests a page from the server, this message is sent back. Cookies are often used to identify users and personalise their visit by customising web pages for them for example by welcoming them by name next time they visit the same site. A site using cookies will usually invite you to provide personal information such as your name, e-mail address and interests.IP (Internet Protocol)All networks connected to the internet speak IP, the technical standard which allows data to be transmitted between two devices. TCP/IP (Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol) is responsible for making sure messages get from one host to another and that the messages are understood.IP addressSPAMUnwanted, unsolicited electronic mail – the internet version of junk mail.Web ServerDelivers (serves up) web pages to your computer.Featured
How British Antarctic Survey use cookies
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're okay with this, but you can opt-out if you wish.Accept Read morePrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy OverviewThis website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may affect your browsing experience.
Necessary
Necessary
Always EnabledNecessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessaryAny cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
